Eldridge Alexander

Ypsilanti, MI | 615.713.1908 | eldridgea@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/eldridgea/ | https://eldrid.ge | github.com/eldridgea

SUMMARY

Security and IT professional with experience in building teams and programs to drive organizational security, profitability, and growth. Champions efficiency and focuses on developing and deploying solutions for a wide range of security and business challenges. Diverse experience in both scaling in smaller companies, as well as effectively leading teams in well established organizations.

SKILLS

- Technology & business strategy
- Docker, Swarm, Kubernetes, Istio
- Bash
- ZFS

- Enterprise IT
- GCP, AWS
- Nginx, Caddy
- Git, CI/CD
- BeyondCorp/Zero Trust
- Python, Django, Flask
- Kvm, libvirt
- DNS, DoT, DoH

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2021 - Present

Associate Director of Cloud Security, Gemini, New York, NY

Established the Cloud Security team. Leading the charge to deploy and provide infrastructure for the security function as a whole. Providing guidance to the rest of the organization, and ensuring that the easiest development path is the most secure.

2021

Information Security Manager, Kong Inc. Ann Arbor, MI

Worked to initiate the Information Security Program

2018 - 2020

Manager of Duo Labs, Duo Security (a Cisco Company), Ann Arbor, MI

Defined and implemented processes for security research, and aligned it with business objectives. Facilitated integration of the team into Cisco after acquisition. Led architecting of next generation security systems, authentication, and authorization technologies.

- Guided team in taking broad research findings and making contributions to company strategies
- Created processes to effectively transfer research results into product features
- Led research into applying modern security to workloads focusing on Docker, Kubernetes, & Istio
- Drove team to "move security left" by integrating security tooling into CI/CD pipelines
- Created communication channels to recognize research and architecture value and allocated resources accordingly
- Guided team through Cisco's acquisition created partnerships with similar teams at Cisco
- Developed methods to internally share research/prototypes that were useful to company strategy
- Led initiatives to build passwordless/WebAuthn tools and communicate them to the company

- Facilitated building of example architecture to demonstrate effective Zero Trust security.
- Wrote papers and presented talks both internally and publicly at industry conferences

2016 - 2018

Head of IT Infrastructure, Cloudflare, San Francisco, CA

Built IT team from the ground up to support the fast growth of employees and tools. Drove the development of automated tooling and effective documentation to facilitate scale. Absorbed tools and shadow IT from other teams into IT team. Drove adoption of modern BeyondCorp/Zero Trust security methodology for IT tool deployment.

- Hired & managed team of 7 to provide support & services to 600+ employees in 6+ offices
- Moved user-facing tools to employ BeyondCorp security principles using Cloudflare infrastructure
- Worked internally to use leanings about deploying BeyondCorp tools to develop Cloudflare Access
- Automated account creation/deletion process across multiple systems reducing onboarding time by 75% and making account deletion more reliable improving company security posture
- Procured and deployed endpoint management systems to maintain and enforce security posture across all endpoints
- Absorbed various systems into IT, changed them to meet security and availability standards
- Created ticket "taxonomies" so as to have reliable metrics to use to determine resource allocation
- Worked cross-functionally to architect scalable directory services, as well as asset and user tracking to satisfy technical and auditing requirements
- Drove documentation, metrics, and asset tracking improvement to meet IPO-readiness needs
- Led subject matter experts to improve processes and documentation in their domains
- Oversaw new office building deployments in multiple cities
- Worked with contract team to make auditorium AV self-service
- Automated regular tasks using Python and Bash
- Created internal short link system on GCP using Python & ensured BeyondCorp access using
- Consulted with PM of Cloudflare's IT-focused products (e.g. Access, Stream, and Spectrum) to make recommendations about product development to serve enterprise IT teams.

2014 - 2016

Operations Engineer, Google, Mountain View, CA

Responsible for a "Techstop" location and providing IT services to my region. Improved and automated common tasks for users in my region. Created and led training for peer and junior engineers on various technologies.

- Led Techstop team of 7 in supporting 7,000+ users
- Created App Engine app to securely and remotely reimage Linux workstations outside the corporate network using Python, iPXE, and Bash.
- Developed processes and signage to facilitate self service for device return, accessory requests, and 2FA enrollment.
- Sat on COE Training Planning Committee
- Participated in long term strategic planning for ITRP Learning and Development
- Created or contributed to "FTLP" learning and development courses including Security, Linux, Android, and ChromeOS.
- Delivered training sessions including Networking and Advanced Security
- Regularly interviewed team candidates

Responsible for providing IT services to Google's global employees. Trained junior employees, and contributed to internal IT automation tooling.

- Worked on global team to remotely support all 100,000+ employees
- Trained new employees on internal tools
- Assisted in creation of automated ticket routing rules
- Added custom "short links" to internal support tool to ease support interactions
- Created and presented TEDx talk on FOSS in education

2006 - 2012

Owner & Engineer, EZap Technology, Murfreesboro, TN

Business owner providing IT and AV consultant services to local SMB companies.

- Business IT support (e.g. email, networking, file servers, laptop endpoints)
- Designed, deployed, and maintained several websites for clients, including ecommerce offerings
- Performed video editing and production for clients
- Published writings in peer reviewed journals
- Worked with contractor to create a web app for mass texting on App Engine

2004 - 2012

Media Specialist, North Boulevard, Murfreesboro, TN

Responsible for providing IT, AV, and networking services to employees.

2010 - 2012

Sports TV Director, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN

Responsible for directing live TV events that were broadcast on CSS or ESPN3.

2008 - 2009

Teacher, Cedar Hall School, Christiana, TN

Responsible for creating and delivering classes on basic technology concepts to middle and high schoolers.

PATENTS, PUBLICATIONS, & CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

Needing the DoH: The Ongoing Encryption and Centralization of DNS, Black Hat USA

Remote Teams in Transition, Duo Blog

Malicious Devices on Hostile Networks at Home, THOTCON

How Technology is Changing Learning, TEDx Oakland

Local Content Caching, TD Commons

Credential Sharing, US Patent Office

Operating System Interface for Credential Management, US Patent Office

Google Docs in the Classroom, Journal for Computing Teachers

Which Web Tool to Select, SITE Conference

EDUCATION

Middle Tennessee State University

Bachelor of Science, Major: Mass Communication, Minor: Theater -- Buchanan Fellow, Honors Graduate